Hope you had a wonderful long weekend.
希望各位度过了个愉快的周末
So,let's jump right into it.
好了 直入主题
So where did we leave last time?
上回说到哪儿了
Last time we talked about the power of the situation,
上回我们谈了环境的力量
we talk about how beliefs become self -fulfilling prophesies.
谈到了信念是如何成为自我实现的预言
And how it is through the situation
以及我们是如何通过环境
that we very often create expectations,believes of people.
对他人产生期望及信念
And these believes become reality.
这些信念会变成现实
And we talked about how social psychology essentially started
还谈到了为什么说社会心理学本质上是从
with some very important experiment such as the Milgrim effect,
某些重要的实验开始的 比如米尔格伦实验
or obedience to authority.
又称权利服从研究
Such as Zimbardo's prison experiment,
比如津巴多的监狱实验
where prisoners were put in or played...
试验中 囚犯被关在...
students play the role of prisoners or the role of wardens
学生扮演囚犯及看守的角色
and they actually entered that role so totally
完全进入了角色 以至于
that after a week the experiment had to be stop,
一周后实验被迫中止
when it was suppose to go on for two weeks.
而原计划是要进行两周
And then the question we asked was,
接着我们提出了一个问题
OK,so we know that the situation is powerful.
既然环境的力量如此巨大
We know that it makes a difference.
能使人改变
Can we also create a powerful,
那能否创造出一种强大但积极的环境
positive situation to bring out the best in people?
将人的最佳状态充分调动起来?
And the answer is yes.
答案是肯定的
And we started talking about it and we talk about professor
我们对此做了深入分析 并谈到了
Langer and her research and how she show that putting
Langer教授以及她的研究
um...elderly men in an environment where they were actually
她让一群老人置身于仿20年前的环境中
or where they acted as if they were 20 years younger
要求他们装作回到20年前的生活
actually became younger.
这些老人竟然变得年轻了
To the point of having higher levels of intelligence.
他们的智力水平提高了
To the point of improving their memory.
记忆力提升了
Improving their eyesight,improving their hearing.
视力听力也改善了
The distance between the bones in their fingers actually
手指骨骼间的距离变长了
became longer which is a sign of younger age.
这是年轻的迹象
They were rated by others as well as by themselves
他们自评及互评都认为
as stronger and younger just because they acted as if
自己更健康 更年轻了
it was 1959 instead of what it was really was,
就因为他们装作自己处在1959年
which was 1979. The power of the positive situation.
而不是1979年 这就是积极环境的力量
And then she did another more research on
她还进行了另一项实验
people going for an eyesight test,
对象要进行视力检查
and put them in a situation in a flight simulator.
他们被安排在了飞行模拟器里
And the exact same eyesight test,
做完全一样的视力检查
they actually performed better just because of the situation.
因为环境的不同 测试结果竟然提高了
And we moved on that what we ended last time
然后我们接着继续讲 上回结束的地方就是
by talking about priming. Priming is...
分析影射 影射是...
can be done in the conscious or subconscious level.
可以从意识及潜意识两个层面进行
It means planting a seed,planting a belief,planting a word,
是指在我们的意识或潜意识中植入
or a picture in our mind,consciously or subconsciously.
一粒种子 一种信念 一个词或一幅画面
And how that actually influences our behavior.
以及如何对我们行为产生影响
So Bargh,that time of NYU,
Bargh在纽约大学时
did the research where he primed to people
进行过一项研究 他用"年老"的相关词
with words associated with old.
影射实验对象
Words if you remember such as wrinkles,
如果你们还记得 这些词包括皱纹
words such as old,words such as Florida.
年老 佛罗里达
And as a result of this priming,
这种影射导致的结果是
those participants in the study actually walked slower,
实验参与者走路更慢了
or actually were more stooped.
更佝偻了
When evaluated by researchers
研究者进行评估时
who were not aware of their condition,meaning they didn't know
并不知道每个对象的实验条件
whether they were primed with control words,
也就是说不清楚他们是被影射了对照词
just random words,or with words associated with old.
随机词 还是年老相关词
So it was just through the priming that people actually
所以通过影射 人们的行为
started to behave differently.
的确会发生改变
The power of the situation. The power of the environment.
环境的力量 外界的力量
And then Bargh took it step further and said,
然后Bargh将实验更进了一步
OK,let's prime the with positive primes such as achievement,
决定用使用积极的影射 比如成就
such as persistence,such as success.
毅力 成功
These words,for example,
比如这些词
they had to find a synonym for the word achievement.
成就的近义词
Those who are primed with these words on intelligence test
实验对象被影射这些词后
and on memory test actually performed better
智力及记忆力测试的成绩
than the control group who wasn't primed with these words.
比没有影射的对照组好
Two Dutch researchers - Dijksterhuis & Knippensberg,
两位荷兰研究人员Dijksterhuis和Knippensberg
what they found was that they brought people,
也进行了影射实验 他们找了一批人
and they ask them to describe for future experiment,
请他们为下一次实验进行描述
not for that experiment.
不是本次实验
For a future experiment,ask them to describe
让他们为下一次实验
the typical day or typical characteristics of three archetypes -
描述三种原型的典型日常行为及其性格:
a soccer hooligan,a secretary and a professor.
足球流氓 秘书及教授
Describe these three archetypes.
描述这三种原型
And they told them this is for the next experiment
他们被告知 这是为下次实验做准备
where we just want people to evaluate these archetypes.
需要这三种原型的描述
Not knowing that actually by describing these archetypes,
但他们不知道的是 通过对原型进行描述
these individuals were primed.
自己已经被影射了
They were primed for a soccer hooligan,for a secretary,
他们分别被影射为足球流氓 秘书
or for a professor.
或教授
And then they have to do intelligence tests afterwards,
影射后 他们接受了智力测试
memory test after those primes.
及记忆力测试
Those who had to describe the day of soccer hooligan
描述足球流氓日常行为的人
performed the worse.
表现得最糟
In terms of memory. In term of intelligence.
无论是记忆力还是智力
Then there was the secretary and those who performed the best
然后是描述秘书的人
were those who described the professor.
表现最好的 是描述教授的人
Now they didn't study any harder before.
而他们之前并没有更努力学习
Nothing changed except for the fact that there was a prime,that
什么也没有改变 除了发生了影射
there was something planted from the environment in their minds.
环境中有东西植入了他们的思想
The question then is,
现在的问题是
how can we create a positive environment for ourselves,
我们如何为自己创造一个积极的环境
where we are primed by the positive,where we can be happier,
让自己受到积极的影射 变得更幸福
more successful and so on.
更成功等等
And there's many ways in which we can do it.
方法有很多
Let me share a few.
我跟大家分享几个
In fact there's going to be your assignment for this week,
其实这将是你们这周的作业之一
or one of the assignments to create a positive environment.
即创造一个积极的环境
So you are some of the examples.
举几个例子
Have pictures of people you love or places you love,the
找一些你爱的人或地方的照片
importance of these things is that even if you don't see them,
这些东西很重要 因为即使你不看它们
you see them. So on the subconscious level it's still there.
潜意识中还意识到它们的存在
Even though on the subconscious level,
虽然只是在潜意识层面
when people are primed,they don't really see...the word,
人们被影射时 看不见...那些词
say achievement on the screen,when it's there for 25 mini-second,
比如"成就"这个词出现在屏幕上25毫秒
they don't really see it,but it registers.
根本不可能看清 但大脑却记录了下来
So even if a picture is there and you don't "really" see it
所以即使你挂了照片但没去看它
or not really conscious of it,mindful of it,
或没意识到它 念到它
it still has a impact on you.
它仍然会对你造成影响
So have pictures of people you love,
所以找些你爱的人的照片
have pleasant object,whether it's memorabilia,
让你开心的东西 无论是纪念品
whether it's flowers,whether it's art,your favorite art.
鲜花 艺术品 你最喜欢的艺术品
So I have in my house,and my office,
我家中和办公室都挂了
my favorite art on the wall,by my favorite artists.
我最爱的画 由我最爱的艺术家创作
And let me share with you a few.
让我跟你们分享一下
I actually brought them here. These are very valuable.
我今天带到课堂上来了 它们价值连城
I insured them,so it's not a problem. So... so this is,um,
我给它们投了保 所以不用担心 瞧
this specific artist from the first phase of his career,
这位画家处在艺术生涯第一阶段时的作品
as you can see,you know,very powerful strokes,
如你所见 充满了有力的线条
very intense,very deliberate,and just gorgeous.
非常强烈 非常从容 真是绝了
And here is,
另外一幅
by the same artist from the second phase of his career.
仍是那位画家 进入艺术生涯第二阶段
Here you already begin to see impressionist influence
印象派对他作品的影响已经清晰可辨了
on his work. But still,you know you see the same trait,
不过你仍能从中看出同样的特点
the same power,the same intensity.
同样的力量 同样强烈的情感
So I have these on my wall.
这些都挂在我家墙上
There's a new and upcoming artist who I want to introduce you to.
我还想向你们介绍一位画坛新秀
She still doesn't have a second phase,
她还没进入第二阶段
you know,she's only one year's old.
因为她才一岁大
But,you know,this is a work done with the help of her Mom.
这幅画是在她妈妈帮助下完成的
But again,these are on my wall and they remind me everyday
但是我还是挂在墙上 每天提醒我
even I've seen them hundreds of time,
虽然我已经看过几百次了
it's still there and I think about my kids.
但还是挂着 让我想起我的孩子们
And I also have other,you know,
我挂了些其他的...
less known artists' work on my wall.
名气不比他们的画家作品
Again,this is,probably not heard of this one,
你们可能没听过这画
um,this is Rodin,The Thinker.
这是罗丹的《沉思者》
And,so I have this on my wall,it's my favorite sculpture.
也挂在我的墙上 是我最喜欢的雕塑
And then I have another piece by Rodin just to remind me
还有罗丹的另一幅作品
that it's not all about thinking,there are other things
提醒我生活不仅要沉思 还有其他的
that make life make life worth living.
让生活更美好
So this is Rodin's The Kiss,for those of you who know it.
这是罗丹的《吻》
And again have these things on your wall
所以找些东西挂在墙上
create(s) the environment where you feel warm,
创造一种让你觉得温暖
where it's fun for you to be there.
觉得开心的环境
Quotes,you know I love quotes,
名人名言 我喜欢名人名言
and I know that many of you love quotes.
你们很多人肯定也喜欢
Some of you have sent me your favorite quotes.
已经有人把他们最喜欢的名言发我了
I have on my wall a list of quotes and they are there
我墙上也有一列名言
even if I don't see them,I see them.
就算我没看它们 也能感受到
So for example,let's see if I brought some here.
比如 让我看看有没有带来
Yes,here they are.
好 在这里呢
So one is by John Quincy Adams.
这句说亚当斯总统说的
"Patience and perseverance have a magical effect before
"耐心和坚持总能奇迹般地
which difficulties disappear and obstacles vanish".
扫除困难和障碍"
So priming the issue of persistence,
将"坚持"用于影射
by the way which is one thing that Bargh did it.
插一句 Bargh的实验也囊括了这个词
He primed that and people actually became more persistent.
受到影射的人的确变得更坚韧不拔
George Eliot,or also known as Mary Anne Evens,
乔治.艾略特 原名玛丽.安妮.艾凡斯
my favorite author. She wrote," The important work of moving
我最喜欢的作家 她写过"推动
the world forward does not wait to be done by perfect men".
人类进步的重任 不能等待完人来完成"
I'll talk about perfectionism which is a very important,
大约三周后 我会讲到完美主义
very personal thing for me in about three weeks.
对我个人来说是非常重要的私人话题
So she is a very much a role model.
可以说她是我的榜样
Camus,"In the depth of winter,I finally learned
加缪说过"在深冬里 我终于发现在
that there was within me an invincible summer".
心里有个不败的夏天"
A quote that has helped me through difficult,through hard times.
这句话帮助我走过了艰难困苦
Henry David Thoreau,
亨利.戴维.梭罗
"If one advances confidently in the direction of his dreams,
"如果一个人能昂首挺胸地朝着梦想前进
and endeavors to live the life which he has imagined,
努力实现他想象的生活
he will meet with success,unexpected in common hours ".
他会与成功不期而遇"
Again,I have these quotes up on my wall,and a few others,
同样地 我都挂在了墙上 还有其他的
that many of the quotes that you've seen in the course.
其中许多名言你们都在课上读到过了
And they prime me,they remind me,
它们不断影射我 提醒我
they create the environment for me.
为我创造出积极的环境
We'll talk about art in the next section,and its importance.
我们会在下一节讨论艺术及其重要性
Have you favorite books next to you. Listen to music,
把喜欢的书放在手边 听听音乐
but listen to it mindfully,
要集中注意听
not just as background music but the music that inspires you,
不要只当背景音乐 要让音乐激发你
whether it's rocky,whether it's Eminem,whoever it is.
无论是摇滚 还是痞子阿姆 都可以
Watch films that inspire you,
多看看激励你的电影
all these things help you to create an environment
这些东西能帮你创造积极的环境
that is conducive to growth,to success,to well being.
有助于成长 获得成功与产生幸福感
A lot of this is done on the subconscious level
其中大部分都是在潜意识层面上进行的
which is the power of the priming. A priming studies.
这就是影射的力量 对于影射的研究
And finally this is what positive research is about.
这也是积极研究的意义
If we constantly focus on "negative" research,anxiety,
如果我们总是关注"消极"研究 焦虑
depression,schizophrenia,we are primed by this research,
压抑 精神分裂症 就会被这些研究影射
we are primed by this work. And it creates reality.
被这些工作影射 创造出现实
You know,this indirectly and conjunctionally relates to,
你们有些人可能知道
some of you may know,the Isenberg principle,
这与冰山理论有这千丝万缕的联系
is that when you measure a phenomenon,
即当你度量某种现象时
you are changing the phenomenon;
就是在改变这种现象
when you are measuring a phenomenon,
当你度量某种现象时
you are also changing yourself.
也是在改变自己
So by researching the positive we are also priming ourselves
所以通过研究积极环境 我们也是在
with the positive.
对自己影射积极的东西
Now,a lot of this work that I'm talking about today and I'll talk
今天包括下周 我谈到的很多内容
about next time actually comes from the self-help movement.
其实都是源于自助运动
In many ways the self-help movement was founded,
自助运动确立于20世纪
was started in the 20th century...
并从各个方面展开
was started with the understanding that we create the world
其理论基础为我们通过思考创建了世界
through our thinking,that our mind creates the world.
我们的思维创建了时间
And books like these came out,back in the 1930's,
1930年代相关书籍开始出版
Thinking Grow Rich.
比如《思考致富》
This book since 1930's sold over 60 million copies.
从30年代至今销售超过6千万本
It's still selling.
而且仍不断再版
It's selling,it's the best seller in the US,
至今还是畅销书 不论在美国
it's the best seller in China,in India,
中国 印度
it's the best seller in Africa,it's the best seller in Europe.
非洲还是欧洲
It has an impact on people and here's one of the things
它对人们产生了巨大影响
that Napoleon Hill says,
作者Napoleon Hill这样说过
"Whatever your mind can conceive and believe,it can achieve."
"只要你想得到 只要你相信 你就能够做到"
Whatever your mind can conceive and believe,it can achieve.
只要你想得到 只要你相信 你就能够做到
Very empowering.
非常鼓舞人心
And this had an impact on many different people,on the masses,
对各类人群 对大众产生了很多影响
again,60 million copies,one of the best sellers in history.
6千万本销量 史上最畅销书籍
Henry Ford had a similar idea,
Henry Ford也发表过类似的看法
"Whether you think you can or can't,you are right."
"不论你认为自己行还是不行 你都是对的"
And people were drawn to this message. Why?
许多人都这一理念吸引 为什么
Because it's empowering,
因为它鼓舞人心
because it makes them feel that things are possible.
让他们觉得没有什么不可能的
Another very influential book,
另一本极具影响力的书
The Power of Positive Thinking,Norman Vincent Peale.
Norman Vincent Peale的《正面思考的力量》
"Have great hopes and dare to go all out for them.
"要有美好的希望 并全力以赴去追求
Have great dreams and dare to live them.
要有远大的梦想 并全力以赴去实现
Have tremendous expectations and believe in them."
要有宏伟的期望 并深信不疑"
How inspiring for people to hear that,
多么让人为之一振啊
all you need to do is think,
只要你思考
all you need to do is believe,and affluence will come to you.
只要你相信 就会获得富足
Whether it's intrapersonal affluence,
无论是精神的富足
whether it's monetary affluence.
还是物质的富足
And this is been the message that has drawn the masses
这一理念对大众一直有着巨大吸引力
and continues to do so today.
时至今日仍是如此
The best selling book today,
当今最畅销的励志书
No.1 best seller all over the world,that's right,The Secret.
全球销量第一 没错 《秘密》
The secret to success is,what they call,the law of attraction.
成功的秘密就是 所谓的"吸引力法则"
The law of attraction is that you attract to your life
即 你的生活是被你吸引过来的
whatever you imaging,whatever you believe it.
无论你想象什么 无论你相信什么
Again,a powerful message,
有一条强大的讯息
millions and millions of copies of this book being sold.
本书已经卖出了几百万本
As we speak,continue to be sold.
就在我们说话当口 仍在热卖
And the message is again simple: believe,and you will achieve;
而它传达的讯息其实很简单:相信就会成功
conceive,and it will be conceived.
构想就会实现
In reality,in the world,it will come to you.
在现实中就会实现
Very convincing,very inspiring message.
让人信服 鼓舞人心
But,is this message right?
但是 这条讯息正确吗
Well,we talked about this and we saw the Roger Bannister story.
这我们讨论过 还有Roger Bannister的故事
You know one day,or six weeks after Roger Bannister runs
他在4分钟 准确说是3'59跑完了1英里
a mile in 4 minutes,or in 3'59,John Landy runs it in 3'57.9.
6周后John Landy将这一成绩缩短到3'57.9
The year after 37 runners run the mile in under 4 minutes.
一年后37名运动员都能跑到4分内了
So there is something to it.
其中有一定奥妙
Once they believed it was possible,it became possible.
一但他们相信能办到 就有可能实现
And here is the issue,
但问题是
with much of what's going on in the self-help today,
当今的心理自助运动的发展趋势
self-help realm today,it draws on a truth,
当今的自助领域强调某个真相
a real truth and then blows it out of proportion.
将这个真相过分鼓吹
So yes,
没错
there is some truth in the fact that our mind creates reality.
某种意义上我们的精神的确能创造现实
But that's only part of the truth.
但是这不是全部
We create reality or rather we co-create reality.
我们创造了现实 或者说是共同创造
There has to be something out there or in there,
还会受到外界或者内在的某些影响
for example,when it comes to The Secret.
比如《秘密》
If you believe that you are likely to succeed,
如果你相信自己可能会成功
you are much more likely to succeed.
那成功的可能性会变大
But that has to come with a lot of hard work and persistence,
但离不开刻苦勤奋与坚持不懈
it has to come with a lot of failure,
而且失败避免不了
and learning from that failure.
你要从失败中学习
So it's just half of the equation and what these self-help books
所以这只是等式的一半 而这些自助书籍
and messages do is overpromise and under-deliver,
传达的讯息往往言过其实 效果甚微
which at times can be destructive.
甚至可能会造成毁灭性后果
For example,if everything is based on the law of attraction.
比如 如果一切皆建立于吸引力法则上
I created everything that
我创造了一切
everything is up to me and also everything is my fault.
一切都因我而变 一切都是我的错
Even taking to the extreme,
举个极端点的例子
is a 3 years old girl responsible for being abused?
如果3岁小女孩被虐待 那是她的责任吗
Is a 30 years old man responsible for being paralyzed
30岁的男子被酒醉驾车的司机撞成瘫痪
as a result of an accident by a drunken driver?
是他自己的责任吗
There are certain things that are out there
有些事情是我们无法控制的
and when we say that everything is up to us,
所以一切因我而变
everything is created by the law of attraction,
一切都由吸引力法则决定
then it's a prescription maybe in the short term for inspiration
这种说法短期内可能能让你
and for belief and for wellbeing,but in the long term,
坚定信念 获得幸福感 但是长期来看
it's for frustration,for guilt,and for unhappiness.
只会让人感到挫败 内疚 不快乐
And also for less success
离成功越来越远
because if I really believe that it's all about thinking,
因为如果我真的相信一切都由思考决定
then this is going to be my mind set.
这种想法就会成为我的心态习惯
All I need to do is believe and then
只要有信心
all the money will come to me.
钱就会滚滚而来
All the success in a relationship will come to me.
爱情就会降临于我
And that does away with the hard work,
这抹杀了勤奋工作...
with the persistence,with the failure that is necessary,
坚韧不拔以及失败的作用
part and parcel of a successful,happy,fulfilling,human life.
它们也是成功 幸福 完满人生的必要组成部分
I want to show you a quick video.
我给大家放一段短片
This is of an ad I saw online and I actually called the
是我在网上看到的一段广告
Royal Bank on Scotland and asked them to send me the original.
于是我向苏格兰皇家银行索要了原版
Because it captures some of the misunderstanding
因为它抓住了当今人们对精神力量的
that there is today about the power of the mind.
某种误解
Just a very cute ad.
很诙谐的一则广告
Douglas from the conference.
Douglas 也是参加会议的
- James Aderson. - Oh,yeah.
- James Aderson - 你好
That's a lot of green.
这儿风景真不错
What kind of bird is it?
那是什么鸟？
- What's that?   - I don't know.
- 怎么回事 - 不知道
It's ok guys! I've done a course.
没事的 各位 我上过一门课程
-What? -Positive thinking.
- 什么? - 正面思考
Positive thought makes a positive impact.
正面的思考会产生正面的影响
OK? Positive thought has a positive impact.
明白不 正面的思考会产生正面的影响
Look at me. That's right. Okay,come on.
看着我 没事的 来
(Emergency Start)
(紧急启动)
Talk is no substitute for action.
语言不能代替行动
That's the power.
这就是思想的力量
Make it happen. The Royal Bank of Scotland Group.
创造现实 苏格兰皇家银行集团
- I am good. - Yes,you are.
- 我真厉害 - 真的耶
It captures part of the truth but not the whole truth.
它抓住了部分真相 但不是全部
So let's see what serious research
我们看看严肃研究
has to say about the power of the mind.
对精神力量的解释
A real phenomenon,actual phenomenon,but one
一种神奇的现象
that we need to also apply real research to see what works.
但还是需要通过实验来研究其原理
Albert Bandura,on your reading about for this week,
Albert Bandura 你们本周的阅读任务
has done a lot of work on the concept of self-efficacy
做了许多关于自我效能的研究
which is essentially the academic term for believing in oneself.
本质上是自信的学术术语
And here is what he writes after decades and decades of research.
以下是他进行几十年研究后的结论
He by the way won the researcher's prize for
去年他获得了授予积极心理学家的
the positive psychologists last year
研究者奖项
so he's doing a lot of research in this area. He's from Stanford.
进行了很多这方面的研究 他是斯坦福大学的教授
"Beliefs in personal efficacy affect life choices,
"自我效能感影响人们生活选择
level of motivation,quality of functioning,resilience to
动机水平 机能的质量 对逆境的适应力
adversity and vulnerability to stress and depression."
对压力和沮丧的抵抗力
Those you believe in themselves,who have confidence,
相信自己的人 充满信心
do well across the different areas in their lives,He continues,
在生活的不同领域都表现出色 他还指出
"People who regard themselves as highly efficacious act,think,
认为自己高效能者
and feel differently from those who perceive themselves
与认为自己无用者
as inefficacious.
想法感觉完全不同
They produce their own future,rather than simply foretell it."
他们创造自己的未来 而不是简单地梦想
In other words,what he's talking about here is that
换句话说 他所说的是
these people are scribed in their lives.
对生活充满信心的人
They create their own lives as oppose to those
他们创造自己的人生 与那些
that are being prescribed by others. They are more resilient,
由他人摆布的人不同 他们适应力更强
better able to deal with hardships and difficulties.
对困难与挫折的应对力更强
In other words,better capacity
换句话说 能力更强
as we discussed earlier to deal with difficulties.
我们之前讨论过应对挫折的问题
Now the important thing about this research,
这项研究的重要性在于 经过长年累月的
in his research over the years is that it can be learned.
研究发现 这些能力是可以习得的
It's cultivated over time.
可以慢慢培养
So it would be useless if,in terms of research,
否则研究就是无用的 至少对我们来说是
at least for us if he would say,
如果通过研究他得出结论
well,some people are born with it,and others are not.
说这种能力只是天生的
Some people are born with,what they started to talk about,
有些人天生就有适应力基因
the resilience gene,and others are not born with that.
其他人没有
But that's not the case.
幸好情况不是这样
What he has shown is that it can be learned.
他的研究表明这些都可以习得的
It takes time,it takes effort,
但要花时间和经历
and we will talk about later how we do it.
我们以后会讨论如何培养
But the important thing,it's malleable.
重要的是 这些能力是可以锻炼的
We can do something about it.
我们可以改变它
Other research by Curry on college athletes,
Curry做过一项关于运动员的研究
I know there are many athletes in this room.
下面一定坐着许多运动员
She showed that 56% of your successes as an athlete,
她证明了一旦成为运动员
once you start being an athlete,is determined by levels of hope,
56%的成功是由期望度决定的
by how much you believe that you are going to succeed.
成功取决于你坚信自己能取得成功的程度
Remember from very first or second class
记得第一或第二节课上
where I talked about the research by John Carter,
我提到了John Carter的研究
about the business...HBS graduates.
有关商...哈佛商学院毕业生的
Where he predicted...
他预测...
where the two things predicted success in the long term,
有两个因素会影响他们的长期成功
extraordinary success of these grads.
某些毕业生会格外成功
One was that they were constantly asking questions,
一是他们不断地提问
and two was that they believed in themselves.
二是他们相信自己
They thought they could do well.
他们相信自己能行
But it's important to also realize that
但需要意识到的是
it's not 100 percent of the variances that was explained,
不是所有这些差异
by hope,or by belief,or by optimism,
都能用希望 信念或乐观来解释的
as many of the self-help books would have us believe.
很多自助书籍想引导我们这么认为
But it's certainly part of the equation of success.
但当然这些是成功的一部分
Nathaniel Branden has been a therapist for fifty years;
Nathaniel Branden从事心理治疗50年了
he's done a lot of rigorous philosophical and psychological
他做过许多严谨全面的哲学及心理学研究
research and work on the concept of self-esteem.
致力于对自尊概念的探究
We'll visit him more in-depth when we talk about,
等我们进行到自尊课时
when we have the week on self-esteem.
会详细讲他的研究
But for now,just a quick quote:
现在我只引用他的一句话
"the level of our self-esteem,in another words,
"我们每个人自尊的水平
the level of our belief in ourselves,
也就是自信的程度
has profound consequences for every aspect of our existence:
对我们的方方面面有着深远的影响
how we operate in the workplace,how we deal with people,
比如我们的待人接物
how high we are likely to rise,how much we are likely to achieve
能取得的地位 能取得多少成就
and,in the personal realm,
还比如在个人领域
with whom we are likely to fall in love,
我们会与谁坠入爱河
how we interact with our spouse,children,and friends,
我们与配偶 孩子及朋友的关系
what level of personal happiness we attain."
个人幸福的水平"
Very low levels of correlation
物质富足与幸福感
between material affluence and wellbeing,
或生活地点与幸福感
or between where we live and wellbeing,
属于低度线性相关
very high correlation between self-esteem and wellbeing.
而自尊与幸福感属于高度线性相关
In most research what we found is a 0.7 correlation
大多数研究发现两者的相关系数
between the two constructs.
可以达到0.7
This is what I found in my dissertation as well.
我的论文也获得了相同结论
So self-esteem matters.
所以自尊非常重要
The internal matters and what we are doing when we enhance
内在因素很重要 我们提高自信水平时
when we raise our levels of belief in ourselves
发生在我们身上的是
is we are transforming our mind,we are changing the form,
我们在转变精神 改变"容器"
so that we see we interact,we see the world differently,
这样我们看世界的角度不同了
we perceive different things,
有了不同的理解与感悟
we experience things in a different way.
处事待人的方法不同了
Whether it's successes that we then celebrate,
庆祝成功
or failures that we then learn from and turn into opportunities.
从失败中学习 转化为机遇
But so much of it is about what we have inside here.
但最重要的是我们的内在
Branden,"self-concept is destiny."
Branden说过"自我概念即命运"
Very similar to"whatever your mind can conceive,it can achieve"
与"只要你想得到 只要你相信 你就能够做到"
from Napoleon Hill.
非常相似 Napoleon Hill说的
The only difference being that he also
唯一的不同之处是
puts a lot of rigorous thinking and research there
他对此进行了严谨细致的思考与研究
and shows the limitation of the belief.
以证明信仰的局限性
Here is another example of research done in the area
这一领域的另一个研究
which most people know about.
大多数都听说过
The Placebo effect.
安慰剂效应
You go to the doctor,you have a headache,
你头痛 去看医生
the doctor tells you: here I have a pill for you.
医生说 我给你开种药
The best thing. Just came out recently.
非常有效 新出的
Will help you get over the headache.
能治疗你的头痛
Gives you the pill. You get over the headache.
你吃了药 头不痛了
Unbeknownst to you,what she gave you was,a sugar pill.
你不知道的是 她给你的其实是糖球
But because you thought,
但是因为你以为
because you believed that it would help your headache,
因为你相信它能治好头痛
it actually did help your headache. Real phenomena medicine.
还真治好了 真是神药啊
So Herbert Benson,from the across the river,
于是Herbert Benson 在河对岸
from the medical school here,
医学院的老师
has done a lot of research in this area.
对此做了一系列研究
Let me share with you just two of his studies.
我着重跟大家讲两个
What Benson did was bringing women who had,
他找了一些处在妊娠期
who were pregnant,and who had stomach problems...
胃部不适的妇女
they were vomiting,they were throwing up,they were nauseous,
她们都有呕吐恶心的症状
something which is relatively common
这其实挺常见的
especially in the first trimester of pregnancy.
尤其是在怀孕初期的三个月
So he brought them in and told them,
他告诉她们
"I have this new pill for you
"这里有一种新药
that will help you overcome your stomach distress.
能缓解你们胃部不适
You won't throw up any more after;
治疗呕吐症状
this is a very powerful and good pill."
非常有效
So he gave them that pill and they got over
于是他把药给了她们
their stomach distress,they were better.
她们的胃部就好了
They didn't know of course this was just a placebo drug,
当然 她们不知道那只是安慰剂
just a sugar pill.
普通的糖丸
Then he took it step further,
然后他将实验更进一步
brought in another group of women with the exact
找来了另一组有同样胃部不适
same stomach distress,with the same vomiting.
呕吐症状的妇女
Gave them the pill,
把药给她们
he told them would help them overcome their stomach distress.
告诉她们可以缓解胃病
Only this time,instead of a sugar pill,
但是这次 他给的不再是糖丸
he actually gave them small dosage,
而是小剂量
not dangerous but small dosage of ipecac.
没有危险性的小剂量的吐根
Now those of you who know what ipecac is...
你们可能知道吐根...
It's a drug that we take if we want to throw up.
是催吐时服用的药物
So if we have food poisoning,
如果发生食物中毒
we take these drugs and it will actually elicit vomiting.
就需要服用吐根催吐
So he gave them this drug and again,
他给这些病人服用了吐根
this passed all the ethic reviews and was not dangerous,you know
这一实验通过了道德审查 没有风险
But that's what he did.
他给这些病人服用了吐根
And these women were told that they'd get better.
并告诉她们能治疗呕吐
And they did get better.
而她们也的确恢复了健康
Not only did they not vomit as they should have done,
本来应该出现的呕吐症状不仅没有出现
more so with the ipecac,they actually stopped.
由于服用了吐根更该呕吐的 实际上呕吐却停止了
Let me read to you an excerpt from his book,
我给大家读一段摘录自他的《永恒的治疗》
which I highly recommend,Timeless Healing.
我非常推荐这本书
I quote,"Remarkably,the patients' nausea
"引人注目地是 病人的恶心感与呕吐反应
and vomiting ceased entirely and their stomach contractions,
完全终止了 且根胃内水球测量
as measured through the balloons,returned to normal.
胃胀现象也消失了 恢复正常
Because they believed they received anti-nausea medicine,
因为她们相信她们服用的是止吐药
the women reversed the proven action of a powerful drug.
竟然逆转了催吐药的作用
Even though many of us stock our medicine cabinets and first aid
虽然很多人在医药箱储存了吐根
kits with ipecac to bring about vomiting in case of poisoning,
以防食物中毒发生
these pregnant women with documented stomach distress thwarted
这些胃部不适的孕妇
the action of a drug that should have made them even sicker.
却抵御了本该让她们更难受的催吐药物
With belief alone,they cured themselves."
单凭信仰就治好了病痛
Now,this doesn't mean that drugs don't have an effect.
但这不是说药物没有效果
You know,I don't recommend going home now and,
我不推荐大家回家以后
you know,giving your roommates,
给你们的室友
you know,ipecac or even worse cyanide
服用吐根 甚至氰化物
and then tell them this is actually Vitamin C.
然后告诉他们这是维生素C
they will probably not feel better or healthier as a result.
他们一般不会感觉好
But what this experiment dose,
但这一实验
and many others like it show is that powerful effect
及其他类似实验表明
of the mind which we shouldn't discard.
我们不应忽视精神的强大力量
We need to study it and understand.
而需要研究并理解它
Well,here is another experiment that Benson writes
Benson在他的书中还写到了另一个实验
about in his book. This was done in Japan.
这项实验是在日本进行的
So,people who are allergic to a specific plant
实验对象对某种植物过敏
were brought into a lab,had their eyes closed,and then,
他们被蒙着眼睛带进实验室
they had these plant touch their forearm,
研究人员用过敏植物碰触他们一只手臂
and then they had another plant touch their other forearm,
然后用另一种植物碰触另一只手臂
and they didn't know which was which.
但没有告诉他们哪边是过敏植物
And of course that plant that they were allergic to,
理论上被过敏植物碰触的手臂
the arm flared up. They were allergic to it after all.
会发出了疹子 出现过敏反应
But then,their was a second condition,
但是 实验还有另一个条件
these people were told that the actual drug(plant)
他们被告知会过敏的植物
that they are allergic to touched their left hand,
碰触了他们的左手
and another plant that they were not allergic to
不会导致过敏的植物
touched their right hand.
碰触了他们的右手
But Benson reversed the effect,
但是Benson将两者对调了
so actually the plant that they were allergic to
即真正会导致过敏的植物
touched their right hand,and the plant that
碰触的是他们的右手 而不会导致过敏的
they were not allergic to touched their left hand.
碰触的是他们的左手
So they were supposed to flare up on the right,not on the left.
所以按理说 应该右手起疹子 而非左手
But because they believed that the allergic plant
但是因为他们误以为左边的才是
was on the left,their left hand flared up,
过敏植物 所以左手起了疹子
their right hand did not.
而右手没有
Based on the power of the mind.
因为精神的力量
Once again,this does not mean that the external doesn't matter
但同样的 这并不是说外在因素不重要
and that we attracted everything that we want to into our lives,
也不说明生活中的一切都是被吸引过来的
but it does mean that the mind plays a very important role
但是这的确证明了精神
in creating our physical,certainly emotional,
对构建我们的生理 情感 认知
cognitive as well as external reality.
以及外在环境起了重要作用
Beliefs very often become self-fulfilling prophecies.
信念常常会成为自我实现的预言
But how does it work? How does it work?
但它是如何作用的呢?
Let me share with you this model that
我想跟大家分享一个模型
I created based on a lot of research in the field.
是我根据这一领域大量研究建立起来的
That essentially tries to explain how our beliefs,
它基本上解释了我们的信念及希望
our expectations impact our performance.
是如何影响我们的表现的
Whether it's through the placebo drug,
无论是安慰剂效应
whether it's our performance in school,in sports,
还是我们学习 体育运动 恋爱关系等
in relationships,in every area in our lives.
生活各个方面的表现
In other words,what comes in the box here?
换句话说 这盒子里是什么
Or in the...over here?
这上面应该有哪些内容?
What comes,what mediate between beliefs,
是什么斡旋于信念期望
expectations and actual performance in the real world?
及实际表现之间?
I want to talk about two mechanisms.
我想谈谈两个机制
The first one is very straight forward,
第一个相对简单易懂
relatively simple,it's motivation.
即动力
So,if I believe that I can do well,
如果我相信我能行
and think about your own past experiences,
各位可以回忆一下自己的经历
when you believe that you could do well in something,
当你相信你能做好某事时
you are much more likely to be motivated
会非常有动力
than if you think that you are hopeless and have no chance,
如果你认为自己希望渺茫
you are much more likely to resign and not do anything.
那就很有可能就此放弃 无所作为
You are much more likely to be motivated before
你不仅事前会受到激励
the event whatever the event may be,in training,in practice,
无论是训练 还是练习
as well as during the event,while it's taking place.
而且正式进行时也会动力十足
Think about what Marva Collins did.
想想Marva Collins的研究
She motivated her students,
她激励学生
she made them believe that they could achieve,
让他们相信他们能获得成功
that they could make something out of their lives
他们一生中能有所作为
and that it's their responsibility that it was up to them,
这是他们的责任
and that made all the difference for them.
这改变了他们的命运
Because they were motivated,they worked hard.
因为他们有了动力 所以非常刻苦
So motivation makes a difference.
所以动力非常重要
There is another thing though,in addition to motivation,
除了动力外 另一样东西也会影响我们
and that is the notion of consistency or congruence.
即一致性或相合性的概念
What dose that mean?
那是什么意思
You see,we all have a mental schema of the world,
我们每个人对世界都存在心理图式
a mental schema of the way the world should be,or to be or is.
世界应该怎么样 会怎么样 是怎么样
For example,I have a mental schema
比如 我的一个心理图式
that suggests that things fall when left in middle air.
表明把东西放在半空会掉下来
So I have a schema that says that if I dropped this,
所以我认为如果我放开这东西
it would actually fall.
它就会掉下来
I have a schema about my ability in mathematics
图式认为我的数学能力
that I might be a good mathematician,
我可能是个优秀的数学家
that I have potential in this area or not.
我在这一领域是否有潜力
I also have the schema about other people. I like this person.
对其他人的态度也有图式 我喜欢这人
That person is a nice person versus
那人真好
this person is just not nice,cruel.
还是那人不好 残忍
So we have schemas about other people,
所以我们对他人 对自己
about ourselves,about natural phenomenon.
对自然现象 都有图式
This is inside,the schema.
图式就是内在
And then,there is the outside world.
还有外部世界
In the outside world,actual things take place.
现实发生在外部世界
For example,when this is left in middle air,it falls.
比如 半空中我松开手 它就会掉下来
This is,has nothing to do with my schema.
这一事实与我的图式无关
It's outside. It happens regardless of my schema.
它发生在外部世界 不管我的图式如何
Now I have certain potential
我在数学上的实际潜力
in mathematics regardless of my schema.
也与我的图式无关
A certain person behaves generously and benevolently
某个人对他人
toward other people or in a hateful manner
是慷慨仁慈还是可憎无礼
toward other people regardless of my schema.
也与我的图式无关
So there is what's inside and what is outside,
所以内部和外部两个因素
and here is the key point.
共同作用就是关键
You see,the mind dose not like when there is a discrepancy
我们的精神不喜欢内部与外部
between what is inside and what is outside.
存在差异
The mind likes when there is consistency,
我们的精神喜欢两者一致相合
congruence between the two,and if there is no congruence,
如果不相合
if there is no consistency,
如果不一致
then we experience a sense of dissidence,
我们就会产生异议感
then we experience disease.
觉得不适
Doesn't feel good,doesn't feel right and we do,very often,
感觉不舒服 不对劲
everything that we can to get the two on par again.
所以我们常常不惜一切 让两者统一
Either by changing the external reality
要么改变外部现实
or by changing our mind to match the external reality.
要么改变自我思维以符合外部现实
We don't like when there is inconsistency.
我们不喜欢不一致
There are a few ways in which
有好几种方法
we can create this consistency again.
可以重建一致性
Let me share with you just some of them,
我给大家介绍几个
and I'm gonna share four. They are interconnected.
我会讲4个 都是互相关联的
There is relationship between. there is overlap,
互相联系 还有重合之处
but just so it helps you to think about it.
但这样能帮助你们就此进行思考
That helps you understand the dialogue that takes place
帮助你们理解内部与外部间
between what is inside or what is inside and what is outside.
发生的对话
So the first thing we can do when there is a discrepancy,
两者差异发生时
when there is inconsistency between the two is update schema.
我们首先能做的就是更新图式
This is the first thing we can do.
这是第一种做法
So,I didn't know things fell when left in middle air,
比如 原来我不知道松开手东西会掉下来
now I know,I updated my schema.
现在我知道了 于是我更新图式
Or,I thought that person was actually hateful,
又比如 我原来以为那人很可恶
but I just saw him behave generously and benevolently,
但我看到他们对别人慷慨仁慈
now I update my schema,he's a nice person.
于是我更新图式 他是个好人
The second thing that we do,
第二种做法
which happens much more often than the first one,
通常比第一种更普遍
is ignore or discard in external information.
即忽视或抛弃外在信息
We ignore and discard external information
忽视或抛弃
that doesn't match our schema.
不符合图式的外部信息
We don't like this inconsistency,
我们不喜欢不一致
we just throw this inconsistency out,
于是直接扔掉这种不一致
so to speak,by ignoring it,discarding it.
也就是忽视 抛弃它
The third thing we do,
第三种方法
we actively seek confirmation.
主动验证
We actively seek confirmatory data.
我们会主动寻求验证信息
I mean,think about No.2 and 3,think about in the real
想想2和3 想想现实世界
you know we are in the midst of election year.
今年正是选举年
Think about the person you are not going to vote for,
想想你不会投谁的票
or the person you didn't vote for.
或者你以前没投过谁
What we do? Very often,let's say,
我们是怎么做的?通常 比如
I see President Bush doing something good,
我看到布什总统做了件好事
actually fighting for a cause that I believe in.
为我信仰的某个事业奋斗
But I didn't vote Bush,for instance.
但我之前没给布什投票 举例而已
Very often what I would do is ignore
于是多数情况下 我会选择
and discard that information,
忽视抛弃这条信息
and then look for confirming evidence that will suggest...or that
然后寻找有利证据以支持...
will confirm to me why I don't like Bush in the first place.
坚定我讨厌布什的立场
This same regarding,say the future elections,Hillary or Obama.
这同样适用于今后的选举 比如希拉里或奥巴马
If I dislike them,I would look for confirming evidence
如果我不喜欢他们 我就会寻找相应证据
why I dislike them and even if they do things
证明我为什么不喜欢他们
that I like and value and believe in,
即使他们做了什么我喜欢 重视或信仰的事
I very often will ignore these things and discard them.
通常我会选择忽视
And what you are doing here,you are creating a reality
我们所做的 就是创造另一个现实
because you are asking a question such as
因为我们在质疑
where has Bush done terrible things or
布什做过什么恶
where has Hillary or Obama did terrible things?
希拉里或奥巴马做过什么恶
And when we ask these questions,
当我们问这些问题时
we completely ignore,discard,not see the positives.
我们已经完全忽略抛弃正面的东西
Remember when I ask you about the geometric shapes?
记得我问你们几何性质吗
You didn't see the children on the bus.
你们没看见车上的孩子
Even though they were right there in front your very eyes.
虽然他们就在你们眼前
So we know that questions create reality,
所以质疑会创造现实
and in order to maintain this consistency,
而为了保持一致性
we do very often one of these two things.
我们常常会采取二者中的一种方法
Either ignore and discard,or seek confirming evidence,
要么忽视抛弃 要么寻找有利证据
positive or negative to back up our schema.
无论积极或消极 来支持我们的图式
Hillary,Obama is good or Bush is good
是希拉里 奥巴马好 还是布什好
or whatever it is that we are thinking about.
或是其他任何看法
The fourth thing is much more directly,creating a new reality.
第4件事直接得多 即创造新的现实
What kind of reality existed before the 6th of May,1954?
1954年5月6日前的现实是什么
It was reality in which four minutes
当时的现实是 4分钟
was the limit of human ability.
是人类的极限 不可能突破
And what did Edison do,sorry,what did Bannister do?
爱迪生做...抱歉 Bannister做了什么
He said it's possible and then he changed the external reality.
他说可能 于是改变了外在现实
Not just for himself,but also for other runners in the world.
不仅是他自己 还有世界上其他赛跑者
And suddenly a new reality was created.
突然间创造了新的现实
Initially the schema was four minutes is not possible,
起初的图式是4分钟不可能跑完
or rather four minutes is not possible
或者说4分钟不可能跑完
and everyone adhered to this schema.
而所有人都拥护这个图式
Roger Bannister came and said,it is possible,
Roger Bannister认为是可能的
and changed that reality,not just for himself,
他改变了现实 不仅为自己
but for other runners who were there.
也为其他赛跑者
The thing though is,that after we perform with high motivation,
事实是 当干劲十足的人达成后
low motivation might looking for consistency.
干劲没那么足的人可能也会寻求统一
All that is left us to do is interpret our performance.
我们需要解读自己表现
Was it successful or not successful,and good or bad?
成功还是不成功 好还是坏
And there are two forms of interpretation.
有两种解读方法
One is the objective interpretation,
一是客观解读
did I just give A in an exam or did I get a C.
我考试得了A还是C
Did I just come third or did I come last in their race.
跑步我是第三名还是最后一名
Did I just be Princeton in hockey on Friday?
周五与普林斯顿大学的冰球赛
Or did I lose to Princeton? Go Harvard. So what happen?
是赢了还是输了?哈佛加油 到底发生了什么?
This is the reality. It's objective,its objective. But then,
这就是现实 客观
there is also the subjective interpretation based on my beliefs.
但同时 还有由信仰决定的主观解读
Let me share an example with you...
举个例子
This is a story told about Thomas Edison.
有个关于托马斯.爱迪生的故事
Thomas Edison,back in the 1870's,
爱迪生于1870年代
was working along with the rest of the scientific community
与科学界都在研究灯泡
on the light bulb,on generating light from electricity.
如何用电发光
The entire scientific community or much of it was working
整个科学界都在研究这一课题
on that,on that issue,with no success,
但一无所获
Thomas Edison being no exception.
爱迪生也不例外
A journalist from one of the local papers
当地报纸的一名记者
came to Thomas Edison to interview.
前去采访爱迪生
He was already famous by then,he invented many things.
他当时已经非常有名了 发明了很多东西
And they were talking about various things
他们谈了各种话题
and then they got to talk about the light bulb.
然后开始讲灯泡问题
And the journalist said to Edison,"Mr. Edison,
那个记者对爱迪生说 "爱迪生先生"
you've been working on the light bulb for many years.
您致力于灯泡研究许多年了
The rest of the scientific community has been working on it,
整个科学界都在进行相同研究
to no avail."
但毫无所获"
Now at that point Thomas Edison had conducted 5000 experiments,
当时爱迪生已经进行了5000次实验
so,and the journalist knew that so he told Edison,
这位记者也知道 于是他对爱迪生说
"Mr. Edison,you've conducted 5000 experiments,
"爱迪生先生 您已经进行了5000次实验
and you failed 5000 times. Give it up."
失败了5000次 放弃吧"
Now Thomas Edison,some of you may know was also hard
你们可能知道 爱迪生听力不好
of hearing,in fact one of his patents was a hearing aid.
事实上 他有一项专利就是助听器
So he said to the journalist," Excuse me,what did you say?"
所以他对记者说"你说什么
The journalist said,"well,I said you failed 5000 times,
那个记者重复"我说你失败了5000次
give it up." So Edison responded,"I didn't fail 5000 times.
放弃吧" 爱迪生回答"我没有失败5000次
I succeeded 5000 times.
是成功了5000次
I succeeded in showing what doesn't work."
我成功证明了哪些方法行不通"
Same objective reality,performance,5000 failed experiments,
同样的客观现实 表现 5000次失败
but very different interpretation.
但却有完全不同的解读
The journalist and many other people
那个记者也其他科学界认定
in the scientific community conclude its not possible,
这是不可能达成的
the interpretation,subjective interpretation of Edison it's just
但爱迪生的主观解读
another stepping stone towards success because it is possible.
却是他走向成功的敲门砖 因为是可能的
In fact,Edison declared,before he had the light bulb,
事实是 爱迪生在发明灯泡前就宣布
that on the 31st of December,1879,
他将在1879年12月31日
he would display the light bulb.
展示灯泡
That was long before he had done it.
这是在他发明灯泡前
On the 31st of December,1879,Edison displayed to the world,
1879年12月31日 爱迪生向世界展示了
generating light from electricity.
用电发光
Just like in 1962,John F. Kennedy said that there would be a man
同样地 1962年 肯尼迪总统说
on the moon by the end of the decade.
60年代末人类将踏上月球
And there was before we had the materials necessary for doing it,
那时我们连登月的物质条件...
before we had other technology necessary for doing it.
科学技术都还不具备
He threw his knapsack over the world
他向全世界放话说
and said it's possible to do it. And that created a reality.
人类能踏上月球 然后创造了现实
That was coupled with a lot of hard work.
这与大量的辛勤工作是分不开的
Edison in fact failed more that 5000 more times
事实上 爱迪生失败了不止5000次
before he actually created the light bulb.
才最终发明了灯泡
It wasn't just sitting his room and saying,
他不是干坐在实验室说
"I believe therefore I will achieve."
"相信就能做到"
It was I believe and I will work even harder now,
而是我相信 而且我会加倍努力
with more motivation and so on.
满怀斗志地工作
One of his mantras,"I failed my way to success."
他的一条名言是"我从失败走向成功"
It is no coincidence that Edison,by far the most creative
爱迪生是史上最富创造力最多产的科学家
and productive scientific genius of all time.
这并不是巧合
he patented 1097 patents in his career.
他一生申请了1097项专利
Much of our world looks the way it looks,
当今世界的发展 大半要归功于他
thanks to him. No coincidence,but the most successful,
史上最成功最富创造力的科学家
creative scientist in history is also,as far as we know,
也是失败次数最多的科学家
the scientist who had failed the most times.
这并不是巧合
Research by Dean Simonton,we'll talk about it more depth
还有Dean Simonton的研究
when we talked about perfectionism.
等我们谈到完美主义时会精讲
Research by Dean Simonton shows that
Dean Simonton的研究证明
the most successful scientists and artists through our history
史上最成功的科学家与艺术家
were also the ones who failed the most times.
也是失败次数最多的
No coincidence that "Babe" Ruth,who hit during many of the years
"Babe"Ruth是职业生涯中全垒打次数最多的球手
when he played the most homeruns,also hit the most strike outs.
他也是三振出局最多的
In five of these seasons,was strike out the most times rather.
其中有5个赛季 三振出局次数最多
The most successful people in history are also very often,
史上最成功的人往往是
the people who had failed the most times.
失败次数最多的
This is a sentence that I'll repeat it over and over again
这一句话我会反复在课堂上重复
in the class and here it is: learn to fail,or fail to learn.
学会失败 从失败中学习
Learn to fail,or fail to learn,
there is no other way to succeed.
成功别无他法
There is no other way to learn,in terms of how to work,
学习如何工作别无他法
and there is no other way to learn in terms of learning
要学习如何在科学 政治或艺术界
how to succeed as scientist,or as a politician,or as an artist.
取得成功 别无他法
The artists,as Dean Simonton showed,who had the most dubs,
正如Dean Simonton指出的那样 纵观历史
the most failed attempts through out history were also
那些有过最多次挫折 最多次失败尝试的艺术家
the artists who were the most successful in the long run.
也是最终看来最成功的艺术家
No short cuts.
成功没有捷径
It's not enough to just sit down and think,
只是坐下来思考
and conceive and believe.
构想和相信是不够的
We need to do much more than that.
我们要做的比这多得多
Martin Seligman,considered father of positive psychology,
Martin Seligman 他被认为是积极心理学之父
has done a lot of work on optimism and pessimism.
做了一些有关乐观主义和悲观主义的研究
And here is what he found.
他发现
What he found was that when it comes to goal setting,
他发现 就目标设定而言
pessimists are realistic in terms of their short term goals
悲观主义者不论在他们的短期目标
as well as in terms of their long term goals.
还是长期目标上都很现实
That's good thing to be a realistic.
现实是好事
Short term goal as well as long term goal realistic.
短期目标和长期目标都很现实
Where as optimists are realistic,sorry,optimists on the other
而乐观主义者很现实 抱歉 乐观主义者与之相反
hand,are unrealistic when it comes to their short term goals,
在他们的短期目标设定上并不现实
but are realistic when it comes to their long term goals.
但对于他们的长期目标就很现实
Why is that? Well,let's look at the model again.
这是怎么回事? 让我们再来看这个模型
So let's take the pessimists first.
我们先来看悲观主义者
They have certain goal,and they have low expectations,
他们有某个目标 他们的期望低
low levels of beliefs,they don't think they would do well.
信念不高 他们不认为自己能做好
Low levels of motivation,their mind looks for consistency,
积极性低 他们的大脑寻求一致
and their performance is usually according to
他们的表现通常取决于
their beliefs and expectations.
他们的信念和期望
And the interpretation is,I told you so.
他们的理解是 我早跟你说了
I told you I couldn't do well here.
我早就跟你说了我做不好
And then everyone else in a chorus says,yes,you told us so.
于是其他人都异口同声说是的 你早就跟我们说了
How wonderfully realistic of you.
你这样现实真是好啊
But then sometimes a pessimist succeeds
但有时悲观主义者超出了自身的期望
beyond his or her expectations.
取得了成功
And then what happens?
那么又会怎么样呢?
The interpretation is,low levels of beliefs,
这时的解释是 低水平的信念
so the interpretation is,well,it was lucky,
那么解释就是 只是走运而已
it was because Mars was in front of Venus,
是因为火星转到了金星的前面
and that only happens once every 50 years,won't happen again.
50年难得一遇 不会再发生了
Or,it was my lucky day,or,she just played very poorly today.
或者 今天是我的幸运日 或者是因为她今天表现得不好
And then,the mind looking for consistency,
于是 大脑在寻求一致
they go around that loop again and again,
一次又一次地重复这个循环
and then become realistic once more.
然后再一次变得现实
Unsuccessfully realistic,but realistic.
不成功的现实 但是现实
So they're realistic in the short term
于是他们在短期目标上
as well as in the long term.
同样也在长期目标上很现实
Let's look at the optimist now.
我们现在来看乐观主义者
The optimist starts with high levels of beliefs,
乐观主义者一开始有着很高的信念
high levels of expectations,motivation,incredibly high.
很高的期望 积极性 非常高
The mind looking for consistency,performance,not so good,
他们的大脑寻求一致性 表现 没那么好
not as good as the expectations were.
没期望中的那么好
In other words,unrealistic.
换言之就是 不现实
However,the interpretation,because of high levels of beliefs,
但是 由于信念水平很高 他们的解释
the subjective interpretation is,
其主观的解释是
OK,so,what if I learn from it? This is an opportunity;
好吧 如果我从中吸取教训了会怎么样? 这是个机会
I've actually got better this time. What if I learn?
我这次其实做得有进步了 就当吸取教训了
And they still have high levels of beliefs
他们依然保持着很高的信念
and high levels of expectations.
很高的期望
Motivation is high,the mind looks for consistency,
积极性很高 大脑寻求积极性
they perform,still not good,
他们的表现依然不好
not as good as they expected,unrealistic.
没有他们所期望的那么好 不现实
But the interpretation,still,what if I learn from it?
但解释依然是 如果我从中吸取教训了会怎么样?
I've gone even better this time.
我这次做得好多了
I've shown what doesn't work. And they continue.
我指出了哪些方法是不可行的 然后他们继续
But then comes the quarrels from the outside and says,
但然后外界的声音就会争吵说
"come on,really,why can't you be realistic
"不是吧 真的么 你为什么就不能现实点
like your good brother or sister,the pessimist."
像你的好兄弟或者好姐妹 悲观主义者那样"
But they believed that they can do it,
但是他们相信他们能做到
and they continue to persist and to work hard again and again.
于是一次又一次地继续坚持 继续努力工作
5 times,10 times,sometimes 5000 even 10000 times,
5次 10次 有时5000次 甚至10000次
until they bring the "unrealistic reality" and make it realistic
久而久之 直到他们带来了"不现实的现实"并让它成真
to match their beliefs over time.
和他们的信念相一致了
So even though in the short term,the reality may not match,
所以即使在短期看来 现实可能不一致
I may run the mile for the next 10 years in 4 minutes
我可能接下来10年跑一英里
and 12 seconds or 4 minutes and 2 seconds.
都要4分12秒或者4分2秒
But I'll get there eventually and make my unrealistic
但我终将到达目标 让我不现实的
"expectations" and goals realistic.
"期望"和目标变成现实
Through a lot of failure,through a lot of hard work,
经历很多失败 经历很多努力付出
through a lot of persistence.
经历很多坚持不懈
What Seligman shows about optimism and pessimism is not
Seligman就乐观主义和悲观主义的内容所展现的
that it's not just some pollyannaish feel-good,
并非只是某种遇事过分乐观的自我感觉良好
you know conceive and believe,kind of approach.
你知道 构想然后相信之类的方式
Rather,it's about how we interpret events.
而是关于我们如何解释事件
So for example,how do I interpret my failure?
比如 我如何解释我的失败?
As end of the story,catastrophe, give it up?
最后的结论是 大惨败 放弃
Or as an opportunity for success?
还是一个通向成功的机会?
So he distinguishes,and we'll talk about it more next time,
所以他 我们下次课会谈到
he distinguishes between interpreting an event
他把解释一件事分为是
as permanent or temporary.
永久的还是暂时的
I just didn't create light from electricity,so that could mean,
我没发明电灯 那么这可能意味着
well,it's not possible and I'll never do it or it could mean,
这是不可能的 我永远也做不到 或者也可能意味着
well,this is another step towards success:
这是向成功的更进一步
showing what doesn't work.
告诉我了什么是不可行的
I've just being turned down from a job that I wanted,
我想要的一份工作被拒了
well,it means I'll never find a job
这意味着我永远都找不到工作
or that's a temporary setback. Let's see what I can learn.
或者这是个暂时的挫折 来看看我学到了什么
Let's see how I can home my search and find,
来看看我怎么样能重新寻找并
eventually,my ideal position.
最终找到我理想中的职位
It's also about being pervasive or specific.
也要看人的态度是一概而论还是有针对性
Pessimists look at things that's being...
悲观主义者认为事物是...
the negatives,being pervasive.
他们一概以消极眼光看事情
Well,I'm just not a good scientist versus...
我不是个好的科学家还是...
well,I just wasn't able to get this experiment right this time.
我只是这一次的这个实验没做好
Or if I get a poor grade on an exam,I'm just stupid.
或者如果考试得了低分 我就是白痴
Pervasive,everything,all or nothing.
看什么都是一概而论 不是全部就是一无所有
Versus I just didn't do well here on this specific exam.
而相反可以认为我只是具体这一次考试没考好
What can I learn from it and how can I do better next time.
我从中能吸取什么教训并且下次如何能考好
This is what optimism and pessimism is. And it can be learned.
这就是乐观主义和悲观主义 而这种态度可以习得
A lot of research in this area...showing how learning to interpret
很多有关这方面的研究...表明学习主观地
events subjectively as optimists leads to much higher success.
像乐观主义者 解释事件可以获得更高层次的成功
Some of you may recognize Matt Biondi. 1988 Seoul Olympics.
你们中的而有些人可能知道Matt Biondi 1988年汉城奥运会
Many people thought that he could equal Mark Spitz
许多人都认为他能追平Mark Spitz
records of seven gold medals.
7块金牌的记录
First race,silver medal. Huge disappointment.
第一场比赛 银牌 巨大的失望
Second race,bronze medal. Huge disappointment.
第二场比赛 铜牌 巨大的失望
Everyone I remembered that very distinctly.
大家 我记得很清楚
People talking about how he falls under pressure,
人们谈论着他如何受到压力的影响
how he is not the person we thought he is.
他不是我们所期望的那个人
Martin Seligman at that point said "no,he's going to succeed"
Martin Seligman在那时说"不 他将会成功"
Why? Because he measured him and many other athletes
为什么? 因为他衡量过他和许多其他运动员
on their levels of optimism and pessimism.
在乐观与悲观方面的水平
And Matt Biondi was a constant optimist.
Matt Biondi一直是个乐观主义者
And he knew he would interpret these "failures",I mean,you know
他知道他会将这些"失败"理解为 我指的是
bronze and silver medals in the Olympics,failures,right?
奥运会上的银牌和铜牌 算是失败 对吧?
But these relative for him expected to win seven golds,failures,
这些相对于他期望赢得7块金牌来说 是失败
he would interpret them not as permanent.
但他不会把它们视为永久性的失败
"I choke. I can't make it in the Olympics"
把"我发挥失常 我不能在奥运会上实现目标"
as pervasive "I can't swim well anymore and win"
视为 "我再也不能游好泳和赢比赛了"
to temporary and specific,which he did exactly that
而只是视为暂时的和特定的失败 他也正是那么做的
and won the next five gold medals.
并赢下了接下来的5块金牌
Surprising many people,not Seligman and his research team
这让很多人吃惊 但Seligman和他的研究小组没有
who knew exactly what his interpretation style would be
他们非常清楚他的理解方式
following these "failures".
屡"败"屡战
Also it associated with social and physical mental health.
这同样也和社会和身心健康有关
For example,our immune system,psychological and physical immune
比如我们的免疫系统 心理上和生理上的免疫系统
system is actually stronger as a result of being optimists.
因为乐观而实际上增强了
Resilience levels,a lot of research by Karen Reivich shows
适应力水平 Karen Reivich的很多研究表明
that if you teach people to interpret things positively,
如果你教人们积极地 乐观地理解事物
optimistically,they are much more likely to succeed.
他们就更有可能成功
Those of you who are interested in more about this,her book,
如果有谁有兴趣了解更多这方面的内容 看她的书
The Resilience Factor,Karen Reivich,fantastic book,
《适应力因素》 Karen Reivich写的 很不错的书
where she talks about programs implemented where within
她在书里讲到了一个为期
a few weeks kids are immune to the experience of depression
几个星期的项目 孩子们此后两年都
two years hence...
对忧郁的经历免疫
People who learn to be optimistic and she teaches them
那些学习如何乐观的人
in a short period as two weeks compare that
她在短短两周时间里对他们进行指导
to the five years of the Cambridge Summerville Study.
并和剑桥Summerville五年的研究做对比
Within as little as two weeks,people who were
在短短两周时间里 那些被教导
taught optimistic interpretation style become happier,
乐观地理解事物的人变得更快乐
those who learn it are eight times less likely
学过的人患上忧郁的可能性
to experience depression.
减小了八倍
Eight times less likely to experience depression,
有忧郁经历的可能性减小了八倍
if you simply learn a different interpretation style.
只是简单地学习一种不同的理解方式
I haven't failed 5000 times;
我没有失败5000次
I've succeeded in showing what doesn't work.
我成功地发现了什么是不可行的
So what if I didn't do well now,
所以如果我这次没做好
I will do better next time or the time after that.
我下次或者下下次会做得更好
People who learn to interpret things more positively
学会更积极地理解事物的人
actually live longer.
事实上活得更长
And we'll talk about some of this research.
我们将会谈到一些这方面的研究
You'll read about a bit of it,the Nun Study and so on.
你会读到一些这方面的内容 修女研究等等
People who interpret things positively
积极地理解事物或者更乐观的人
or more optimistic actually live longer.
事实上活得更长
Now that does not mean that all pessimists die young
那并不是说所有的悲观主义者都短寿
and all optimists die old.
而所有的乐观主义者都长寿
That's just one of the factors that goes into the equation,
那只是这个等式里的因素之一
there's many other things.
还有其他的因素
You know,you don't want,there is also unrealistic optimism
你知道 也有不现实的乐观主义
that we'll talked about it in a minute.
我们稍后会谈到
You know a person is optimist and says,
你知道 一个乐观主义者说
"I'll live to 120 no matter what"and smokes,you know,
"无论如何 我会活到120岁"他有吸烟的习惯
120 cigarettes a day would probably not live to 120.
但一天抽120支烟很可能活不到120岁
So it's not just about the belief,but a lot of it is.
所以这不只是只是信念 还有很多因素
And finally,as I mentioned time and again,it can be learned,
最后 正如我屡次提到的 它是可以习得的
and we'll talk about how it can be learned and how we can learn,
我们将讨论要如何学习它 我们能怎么学
and you'll do it whether it's in your response paper,
而在你的课后论文里 你们将研究这个问题
not for this week,but for the next week,
不是这周的 是下周的论文
as well as in sections,as well as by yourselves.
或者是通过分组作业 或者独自完成
A technique that can be learned
一种能被习得
and can have all these positive effects.
并有所有这些积极效应的方法
Okay.
好吧
There's a problem here though.
但是有一个问题
You know,how do I distinguish between this
我要如何区分这两者
and realistic optimism and unrealistic optimism.
现实的乐观主义和不现实的乐观主义
Detached optimism that is advocated in for example
用盲目乐观主义做例子
for self-help movement.
对于自助运动而言
Is everything that I think of I achieve
是不是所有我认为我能实现的
and conceive and becomes a reality?
我构想的都能变成现实?
Is my self-concept my destiny and my only destiny?
我的自我概念是否我的且是我唯一的命运?
Or is there such a thing as unrealistic beliefs?
或是否存在所谓的不现实信念?
And there is such a thing as unrealistic beliefs.
确实存在这样一个东西
Here is an example.
下面是个例子
Her name was Rena,she was a showgirl,at least to me,she was.
她的叫Rena 是个歌舞女郎 至少对我来说她是
Rena and I had a great deal in common.
Rena和我有很多共同点
We were both in our teens, I was twelve. She was fourteen.
我们都十几岁 我12岁 她14岁
We both were in our fives.
我们都5英尺高
She was 5'6. I was 5'1. I was in love with Rena.
她5英尺6英寸 我5英尺1英寸 我爱上了Rena
Rena too was in love with herself.
Rena也爱她自己
Now,just as a side note,I have a wonderful mother,
现在 只是做个边注 我有一个很棒的妈妈
and amazing mother who believes in me.
很好的妈妈 她相信我
And in fact when the three of us.
而事实上当我们三个
We were three brothers and sisters would come home from school.
我们三兄妹放学回家时
We would very often talked to our mom about everything
我们经常会跟妈妈讲学校里
that was going on in school,good and bad.
发生的所有事 好事还有坏事
So I came home after I realized that I was truly and madly
我有一天回家 意识到我是真心地 疯狂地
in love with Rena and that she was the one for me.
爱上Rena 她就是我的真命天女
I came home and talked to my mom about it.
我回到家 告诉了我妈妈
And I told her,"Mom,I love her so."
我告诉她 "妈妈 我那么地爱她"
So she said," what's the problem?"
于是她说 "那问题是什么?"
And I explained to her that she was older that I was
我就跟她解释了她比我大
and all the big boys in the school were interested in her,
学校里的那些大男生也对她有兴趣
that she was much taller than I was.
她比我高多了
And my mother believed in me and went on
而我妈妈对我有信心 她采用了
self-fulfilling prophecy campaign.
自我应验预言的那一套
And though she had never read Napoleon Hill,
尽管她从没读过Napoleon Hill
she said to me,"Tal,whatever you conceive,
她对我说 "Tal 只要你想得到
whatever you believe,you can achieve."
只要你相信 你就能做到"
And though she had never read Branden,she said to me,
尽管她从没读过Branden 她对我说
"Tal,your self-concept is destiny. And Rena is your destiny."
"Tal 你的自我概念就是命运 而Rena就是你的命运"
And she told me that if I truly,truly believed that I could,
她告诉我如果我真的真的认为我可以
that Rena would want me. She really would want me.
相信Rena会喜欢我 她就真的会喜欢我
And my mom inspired me and made me believe in myself.
我妈妈激励了我 让我相信自己
So I went ahead to approach Rena,and I prepared for it.
于是我去接近Rena 我做好了准备
I really prepared for it.
我认真做好了准备
Though I wasn't shaving at that time,I put on aftershave.
虽然我那时还没有刮胡子 但我喷了些须后水
And I continued.
然后我继续行动
I can do it. I know I can.
我可以做到 我知道我能
And I approach Rena,but then the music stopped.
我走进Rena 但这时音乐停止了
And though I had very high expectations,
尽管我期望很高
and though I envisioned success.
尽管我预想我能成功
I closed my eyes and I saw myself succeeding.
我闭上眼睛 我看到自己成功了
She was not interested. She didn't want me.
她没有兴趣 她不喜欢我
However,however,we became very good friends.
但是 但是 我们成为了很好的朋友
In fact so good that she would tell me about
事实上我们关系那么好 她会跟我谈论
all her shallow and tall boyfriends.
她那些肤浅的高大的男朋友们
Now when my mom told me that she really believed in it,
当我妈妈告诉我她真的对我有信心
that she thought I was,you know that she told me this in Yiddish
她认为我是-- 她用意第绪语对我说
and she said "foreign language"
她说(意第绪语)
which means in Yiddish "you're a big find."
在意第绪语里的意思是 "你是个大发现"
I was really my,you know,really,
我真的 真的就是
I was my Jewish mother's kosher Pygmalion.
我那犹太母亲心中符合犹太教规的皮格马利翁
So bad,yeah.
好烂的比喻 我知道
You know,that took me a lot of time to think about,
那句话花了我不少时间想出来的
you'd better appreciate it.
你们最好表示一下喜欢它
But...thank you,thank you. But it didn't work.
但是...谢谢 谢谢 但这没有用
And again,don't get me wrong,I'm very grateful to my mom.
再一次 别误解我 我非常感激我妈妈
I literally had 24/7 Marva Collins in my house.
简直就像是全天候的驻家Marva Collins
I owe so much to my mom. However,in this case,
我是那么地感激我妈妈 但是 这一次
it probably was not the realistic belief.
这可能不是现实的信念
So what is realistic?
那么什么是现实的?
How do we identify what is realistic and what is not?
我们如何区分什么是现实的 什么不是?
Here are some ideas to help us do so.
下面是一些对我们有帮助的想法
The Stockdale paradox.
斯托克代尔悖论
It's about finding the tension,
它认为要找出矛盾
reconciling the tension and it's not easy.
让矛盾化解 这并不容易
Again,I'm not going to give you a formula now to tell you:
我不会给你们一个公式 告诉你们:
OK,here is...calculate this,and if it's above seven,
好吧 就这样...算这个 如果是大于7的
go ahead with green; below seven,probably not so.
就没有问题 低于7的 可能就不是这样
There is no formula. But here is,just a heuristic,
不存在什么公式 但是 仅作为一个启发式
something to think about when you think about beliefs.
当你思考信念时 存在一些需要思考的东西
James Stockdale was admiral. James Stockdale was the highest
James Stockdale是名海军上将 他是
ranking prisoner of war in the... in the Vietnam War.
越南战争被俘人员里级别最高的战俘
And he started to notice a phenomenon. He was there for years.
他开始注意到一个现象 他在那关了很多年
Eventually got out and live to tell the tale many others did not.
最终被释放并得以活着向人们讲述往事 而其他许多战俘没能做到
And he saw many people survive,many people not survive.
他看到许多人幸存 许多人死亡
The very harsh conditions of the prisoner.
战俘的生存条件非常恶劣
What he was that the people who survived had two characteristics.
他发现那些活下来的人有两个特点
First of all,they believed that they would get out,
第一个 他们相信他们能出去
they had faith that one day they would be free.
他们坚信终有一天他们会重获自由
They would get to see their family,their friends.
他们会再见到自己的家人 朋友
And this faith kept them going.
这种信念支持着他们走下去
At the same time,and this is the second component,
同时 也就是第二个特点
they had realistic beliefs and evaluation of the situation.
他们有着现实的信念 能对情况做出估计
If any one of these two components were missing,
如果这两点有一点没做到
they were unlikely to survive.
他们就不大可能活下来
If they didn't have faith and they didn't believed it they would
如果他们没有信念 他们不相信他们会活下来
survive,they were very likely to die in the harsh conditions.
他们很可能在恶劣的环境下死去
On the other hand,if they thought that
另一方面 如果他们认为
they would get out by this coming Christmas,and really
他们能在这年的圣诞节之前就出去
believed that they would get out by this coming Christmas,
并真的相信他们能在这年的圣诞节之前离开
they were also less likely to survive.
他们同样也不大可能幸存
Because they didn't get out by this coming Christmas,
因为他们这年的圣诞节没有被放出去
and then they were desponded,resigned,helpless,
他们失望 气馁 无助
and very often,they died.
通常情况下 他们会死去
So it was the two components,believe that you would get out,
所以关键是这两点 相信你会出去
but at the same time know that you need to
但同时明白自己需要
deal with reality and that it's tough.
应对现实 残酷的现实
Here is what James Stockdale said,
James Stockdale如是说
"you must never confuse faith that you would prevail in the end
"你不能把坚信自己最终会在
which you can never afford to lose
输不起的情形下取得胜利的信念
with the discipline to confront the most brutal facts
同直面现有残酷现实的行为
of your current reality whatever they might be."
相混淆 无论是何种残酷现实
Realistic optimism.
现实的乐观主义
Now the thing is that you may be wrong at times.
现在的问题是你可能有时会错
And sometimes you may really believe in something,
有时你可能真的相信什么
and believe it that you have realistic expectations
相信你有现实的期望
and not succeed.
但没有成功
But as we talked about...And as we'll talk about in a few minutes,
但就像我们谈到的那样...我们接下来会谈到
it doesn't matter that much.
这也没太大关系
Because even if we don't success we just bounce back up.
因为即使没有成功 我们能很快恢复动力
And continue working hard.
继续努力工作
The key though is as much as possible,to attain this balance.
而关键就是尽可能地保持平衡
What Maslow calls The Graceful Integration
这就是Maslow所说的高水平信念
between high level of beliefs and connection to reality.
和与现实联系间的完美整合
No prescription here.
这个不是答案
But just a heuristic,something to keep in mind.
只是一个启发 让你们记在脑子里
Positive thinking is not THE secret.
积极的思考不是秘密本身
Yes,it's part of the secret.
是的 它是这个秘密的一部分
Yes,it's part of the success formula.
是的 它是成功公式的一部分
Yes,it's part of the happiness formula. But it's not all.
是的 它是幸福公式的一部分 但并非全部
False optimism sooner or later means disillusionment,
错误的乐观主义迟早意味着幻灭
anger and hopelessness.
愤怒和无望
Here is the secret of success.
成功的秘密是
This is the secret proven by research.
这是一个经研究证实的秘密
Thousand of years of research and successful people
多年对不同文化 不同地方
in different cultures,in different places and in different ages.
不同年龄的成功人士的研究
It's optimism,passion and hard work.
这个秘密是乐观 热情和勤奋
It'll be very hard for you to find successful men and women
纵观历史 你很难找到哪个成功人士
through out history who did not have all three.
是不具备这三个品质的
Optimism,belief,faith that they can do well,
乐观 信念 坚信他们能做好
that they can succeed.
坚信他们能成功
Passion,love for what they were doing. And hard work.
热情 热爱他们从事的事业 并且勤奋工作
There is no substitute for hard work as Edison said.
正如爱迪生所说 没有什么能代替勤奋
These 3 components. The secret...simple,straighforward.
这三个要素 就是这个秘密...很简单 很明确
You know it all. Remember what I said during 2nd class.
你们都知道 还记得我第2次课上说的么
I'm not going to teach you much new.
我不会教你们新的知识
I hope to remind you what you already know.
我希望使你们想起你们已经知道的知识
Optimism,passion and hard work.
乐观 热情和勤奋
Does luck play a role? Absolutely.
那运气是否也有作用呢? 当然了
Jefferson,"I am a great believer in luck,
Jefferson说"我非常相信运气
and I find that the harder I work,the luckier I get."
我发现我越努力工作 我的运气就越好"
There is actually science behind luck.
运气背后实则也有科学奥妙
And you'll read about it in the Luck Factor.
你们会在《幸运要素》里读到
Where people who have these 3 components,
在书中 拥有这三要素的人
who believe they can do well,
相信自己能成功的人
who love what they do and work hard,
热爱自己的工作并勤奋努力的人
actually find more luck.
事实上获得了更多的运气
In the words of Thoreau in Common Hours.
用梭罗的话说就是不经意间有了更多的运气
Okay,so why don't all the parents
好的 那么为什么不是所有的家长都
teach us to have high expectations?
教我们要有高的期望呢?
If it's so good for us,if it's related to success,
如果这对我们来说有好处 如果这和成功有关
to happiness,to physical well-being,
和幸福 和身体健康有关的话
why don't all our parents just say to us whatever we work,
为什么不是所有家长都对我们说不管你们做什么
you can succeed,you can do it.
你都能成功 你都做到
If you dream about it,you can do it.
如果你梦想 你就能做到
Why did very often parents and people
为什么父母和其他关心我们的人
who care about us lower our expectations?
常常要降低我们的期望呢?
Because they are concerned about our happiness.
因为他们关心我们的快乐水平
They are concerned about our self esteem.
他们关心我们的自尊
You see,there is a lot of belief...People believe that
有很多种信念...人们相信
high expectations naturally lead to disappointment.
高期望自然地会导致失望
So...high expectations lead to disappointment.
所以...高期望导致失望
And it sounds right. I mean,this is the formula that
这听起来是对的 这就是
was written in the 19th century by William James.
William James在19世纪写下的公式
He said that self-esteem is equal to
他说自尊等于我们的成功
our success over pretensions. In other words,our achievement...
除以抱负 换言之就是 我们的成就...
how much we succeed,how much we achieve over
我们有多成功 我们取得了多少除以
what we pretend or what we aspire to,what our goals are.
我们假装或期望所能取得的 我们的目标
In other words,if we have high expectations,high pretensions,
换言之 如果我们有很高的期望 很高的抱负
we are much more likely to hurt our self-esteem.
我们就有更大的可能伤害自己的自尊
For example,let's say my aspiration,my pretension,
例如 比如说我的渴求 我的抱负
my expectation is to make 4 thousand dollars a month.
我的期望是一个月挣4千美元
Again this...I just throw in a numeric
重申一下...我只是举了个数字化的
example here because it's easier to understand.
例子 这样便于理解
Let's say my hope is to make 4 thousand dollars a month.
让我们假设我的希望是一个月挣4000美元
That's my pretension.
那是我的抱负
But in fact what I end up making is 2 thousand dollars a month.
但实际上结果我一个月挣到了2000美元
According to William James' formula,my self-esteem,
根据William James的公式 我的自尊
and as we know self-esteem and happiness
而我们都知道自尊和快乐
are very highly co-related and related.
是紧密相关的
My self-esteem,my happiness level
我的自尊 我的快乐水平
according to this formula is a half.
根据这个公式便只有一半
On the other hand,let's say my pretensions,
另一方面 假设我的抱负
my expectation is to make 1.5 thousand dollars a month
我的期望是一个月挣1500美元
and in fact I make 1.5 thousand dollars a month.
而事实上我一个月挣了1500美元
According to this formula,my self-esteem,
根据这个公式 我的自尊
my happiness level is 1.
我的快乐水平是1
So here even though I'm making less,
尽管我挣的更少了
again I'm using a numeric example here,
我这里举的是数字化的例子
you can think about other examples.
你们可以想想其他例子
Even though I'm actually making less here,
尽管我实际上挣得少了
my self-esteem and my happiness are higher.
我的自尊和我的快乐程度却变高了
So lower you expectations.
所以要降低你的期望
Not so.
其实不尽然
What was found in the last 35 years of research
过去35年的研究发现
is that this formula is actually wrong.
这个公式实际上是错的
That's not the case.
情况不是这样的
Here is how it actually works.
这才是实际的情况
Let's say we have a graph. And this is time.
让我们画一张图 横坐标是时间
And here is my self esteem levels and happiness levels.
纵坐标是我的自尊水平和快乐水平
And let's at start off around my base level which is here.
让我们从我的基础水平开始 就在这里
And then I had a mid-term in Positive Psych.
然后我参加了积极心理学的期中考试
And I don't do as well as I expected to.
我考得没有我期望的好
What happens to my self-esteem? What happens to my happiness?
我的自尊会发生什么变化? 我的幸福会发生什么变化?
Of course it'll go down. It's natural
当然它会下降 这很自然
we all want to succeed or most people want to succeed.
我们都想成功或者说大多数人想成功
So it goes down if it's below my expectations
所以如果低于我的期望它就下降了
but very quickly as the research by Daniel Gilbert
但很快 如Daniel Gilbert
shows on effective forecasting...
有关有效预测的研究表明...
very quickly we go back up to our base level of happiness.
很快我们又回到我们的基础快乐水平
And then a week later I have another mid-term in say,maths 55.
接着一个星期后 我又考了 比如说55号数学课的期中考试
And I ace it. I get much higher grade than I expected.
我考得很好 比我期望的成绩还要高
And what happens to my self-esteem and happiness? It goes up.
我的自尊和快乐曲线又会怎么变化? 它上升了
But then very quickly it goes back down again.
但然后很快它又降下来
And then let's say I'm 12 years old and I walk down
然后我们假设我是12岁 我在街上走
the street and I meet Rena and I ask her out.
我遇到了Rena 我约她出来玩
And she says no.
她拒绝了
What happens to my to my self-esteem and happiness?
我的自尊和快乐水平会发生什么变化?
It goes down. Slightly.
它下降了 轻微地
And then very quickly it goes back up again.
然后很快它又重新上升
And then lucky me. I walk down the street.
然后我很幸运 我走在街上
I think I see Rena but there is something different about her.
我以为我看到了Rena 但她有些不同
And it turns out she has a twin sister.
原来是她的孪生妹妹
And I ask her out. And she says no.
我约她出去 她拒绝了
And what happens once again? Slightly down.
再一次 发生了什么变化? 轻微地下降
But then I recover and go back up again.
但然后我恢复了 又再次上升
And you won't believe it. They are identical triplets.
你们是不会相信的 她们是三胞胎
And I meet the 3rd sister and she says yes.
我碰到了老三 她答应了
She says I love you too.
她说我也爱你
And what happens to my to my self-esteem and happiness?
我的自尊和快乐水平发生了什么变化?
It goes up slightly right? Even taller than this.
它轻微地上升 对吧? 甚至高出了黑板
But then very quickly back down to base level
但然后很快又下降回基础水平
and so on and so on. The vicissitudes of life...
如此反复 生活中的悲欢离合
whether I get tenured or not tenured,
不管我是得到了终身职位还是没得到
whether I win the lottery or lose money.
不管我买彩票是中奖了还是输钱了
The ups and downs around a base level of well-being.
在幸福的一个基础水平上下起起伏伏
Now there is good news here and there is bad news here.
现在有个好消息也有个坏消息
The good news is I can take more risks.
好消息是我能承担更大的风险
It's not the end of world if she says no.
她拒绝我不是世界末日
It's not the end of the world if I fail here
我失败了或者没能得到理想的工作
or if I don't get my dream job.
也不是世界末日
It's okay. I'll recover. We all do. So that's the good news.
没有关系 我会恢复 我们都会 所以这是好消息
The bad news is...so I'm stuck?
坏消息是...我就卡在这了?
So I was born with this base level according to my genes
我根据我的基因生来就是这个基础水平
and I can't really improve?
并且不能提高吗?
How do I raise this base level of happiness?
我如何提高这个快乐的基础水平?
And it's possible. And we'll talk about...
这是可能的 我们会讲到...
the whole course is about raising the base level of happiness.
整个课程就是关于如何提高快乐的基础水平
But here is one finding
但这有一个发现
from specifically the research on self-esteem.
是从专门针对自尊的研究中得来的
On one thing you can do right now when you get out of class
你下课之后马上能做的一个实验
to raise self-esteem and that is to cope as opposed to avoid.
来提高自尊 就是去面对而非逃避
To cope meaning to put yourself on the line.
去面对意味着把自己置身于风险线上
To take risks not when you're in your panic zone
不是要你在恐慌时冒险
but when you're in your stretch zone.
而是在你放松时放手一搏
To risk failure. To handle things,to deal things,
去承担失败的风险 去解决 去处理
to confront things that are important to you.
去面对那些对你来说重要的事情
To try out for that play. To speak out in session if you haven't.
参加戏剧试演 讨论时说出未曾表述出的观点
To go out to a place where you really want to go
去你十分想去
but never really try. To try.
却从没去过的地方 去尝试
Because people who cope overtime have the same
因为那些经常面对问题的人有着同样
or sometimes more ups and downs.
或者有时频繁的起起伏伏
But their ups and downs look like this.
但他们的起伏线条是这样的
Still ups and downs. Permission to be human.
依旧是起起伏伏 和普通人一样
But the base level increases.
但基础水平提高了
Why does the base level increase? I'm gonna end here.
为什么基础水平提高了? 我将以此结束本节课
Why does the base level increase when we cope rather than avoid?
为什么当我们不是逃避而是面对时
For 3 reason.
基础水平提高了? 三个原因
First self perception theory. Daryl Bem...
首先是自我知觉理论 Daryl Bem...
I think from either Dartmouth or Cornell...
我不记得他是达特茅斯学院还是康奈尔大学的了
what Daryl Bem showed was that we derived conclusion
Daryl Bem指出我们得出关于自己的结论
about ourselves in the same way
和我们得出关于他人的结论的
that we derived conclusion about others.
方式是一样的
So for example if I see a person going up to people
比如说看到一个人走到大家面前
and initiating a conversation or speaking up in session
发起谈话或者在会上发言
or trying out for a play and trying again and again.
或者去参加一出戏的试演并一次又一次地尝试
My conclusion about this person is this person is courageous.
我关于这个人的结论就是这人很有勇气
This person must have high self-esteem.
这人肯定有很高的自尊
And I may derive the conclusion about myself
我可能也是用同样的方式
in exactly the same way.
推出关于自己的结论
By seeing myself behaving a certain way,
通过观察自己某些方式的行为
I reach a conclusion about my self-esteem
我会得到关于自己自尊或者
or benevolence or generosity or whatever it is.
仁慈或者慷慨或者其他方面的结论
Self perception theory. And if I cope,if I try things out
自我知觉理论 如果我面对了 我尝试了
then I see that this is a person with courage.
那我就认为这是一个有勇气的人
This is a person who tries. And my conclusion
这是一个敢于尝试的人
about myself would be I must have high self-esteem.
得到关于自己的结论就是我肯定有很高的自尊
And my self-esteem as well as happiness level
我的自尊还有幸福水平
overtime will actually increase.
久而久之就会上升
Self perception theory.
自我知觉理论
We derive conclusion about ourselves
我们得出关于自己的结论
in the same way we derive conclusion about others.
和我们得出关于他人的结论的方式是一样的
Meaning by looking at behavior.
就是通过观察行为
When we fail after coping we realize that the actual pain
我们在面对失败后会意识到
that comes with failure is far less than the pain we imagine
真正来自于失败的痛苦远小于我们想象的
and that we associate with failure.
我们认为与失败有关的痛苦
I just got over it. Okay,so I didn't do well in here
我克服失败 是的 我是没做好
or she said no. but I got over it.
或者她是拒绝了我 但我克服了
Whereas I imagine it in my mind I think it'll last forever.
但我一直在想的话 我就会认为它将一直持续
Just like those tenured or not tenured professors thought
正如那些终身职位或者非终身职位的教授
that their pay will last forever whereas it goes away.
以为他们的薪水将永远不变 其实并非如此
So when I realize the pain of actual failure is far
所以当我意识到实际上的痛苦
less than the pain associated with failure,
比和失败有关的痛苦远远要小时
I become more confident. I can handle it.
我变得更自信了 我能应付了
I'm actually much more resilient than I thought I was.
我实际上比自己想象中要更有适应力
And my self-esteem increases.
我的自尊水平上升了
My happiness as a result increases too.
我的快乐水平也随之升高
And finally there is more success
最后还有更多的成功
because there is no other way to succeed.
因为成功别无二法
There is no other way in terms of learning how to walk.
学习走路没有别的方法
There is no other way in terms of succeeding in art
在艺术上或科学上或商业上或政治上
or in science or in business or in politics.
取得成功没有别的方法
Learn to fail or fail to learn. I'll see you on Thursday.
学习失败 从失败中学习 我们星期四再见